Thank you.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You may be seated.
Thank you.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Hallelujah.
(Amen.)
The foolishness of satan is a strategy to separate the house and destroy the family.
That will take us to the message today: "Let go offence".
Let someone say, "Let go offence".
Viewers at home, thank you.
I want to greet the Church once again, "Good morning".
Viewers all over the world, wherever you are, Jesus is there.
The state of our heart matters; Jesus is there.
We are there and you are also here.
The state of your heart matters.
The state of your heart must be the best.
We are going to take our message today from the Book of Luke 17.
The titles there are: sins, faith and duty.
Don't forget you are a spirit and I want to believe I am talking to a spirit.
Say, "I am a spirit; I live in a physical body".
Once you know that, you will not allow this physical body to control you.
Don't let whatever is outside to control you.
You allow your spirit to control you because your spirit is controlled by the Holy Spirit.
Say to yourself again, "I am a spirit, living in a physical body".
I cannot hear you.
(I am a spirit, living in a physical body.)
You are only learning to live in this natural world.
How to walk, how to talk, how to look...
You are learning to live in this natural world; you are a spirit.
Hallelujah.
So, Luke 17 verse 1:
"Jesus said to His disciples, 'Things that cause people to stumble are bound to come'."
That is, it is impossible to avoid it.
It is just a declaration that it is impossible for you to live in this world without an offence, without being offended.
It is impossible.
So, how to handle this offence is the issue now.
Our response to offence determines our future.
We are going to look at the strategies satan, the enemy of our souls, uses to trap us,
get us and connect us to himself.
Demon's strategy.
As you listen, I see God touching your heart.
(Amen.)
That means you must listen; you have to give me your heart.
As you listen, I see Lord Jesus...
This is a vision; this is what I have seen already.
It has not happened but I have seen it happen.
You just need to listen now.
I see the Lord touching your heart, in Jesus Christ's name.
(Amen.)
Hallelujah.
Yes.
These are the strategies that satan, the enemy of our souls, uses.
His deceptive and deadly traps for us are hidden.
They are not open just like that.
He will not come to you saying he is satan or demon.
He will come as a friend but it is over to you to examine that friend, to know whether he is friend or enemy.
He always uses something we love, are attracted to, value and appreciate -
money, women to men, men to women, position, power.
That is satan.
He will not just come to you and say, "Hey!"
He will pretend to be your friend.
This is why the whole thing at the end will come as a surprise, "Ah, I never thought. Oh my God."
He comes under cover as an angel of light and peace.
It takes the spiritual strength and grace of one grounded in the Word of God to separate good from evil.
Inner my heart
Lord I want to be like Jesus inner my heart
It takes the spiritual strength and grace of one grounded in the Word of God
to identify the traps for what they are, to identify the tricks of satan for what they are.
If you are not grounded in the Word of God, you cannot just say, "Oh no, you are satan. Get behind me."
You must be grounded in the Word of God to be able to examine, differentiate and separate.
He comes under cover like an angel of light and peace.
Going by Luke 17 and 1 Corinthians 8:1, one of the most common traps used by satan is offence.
LET GO OFFENCE
It is impossible to live without being offended.
Because of that, he now uses that offence to get people.
For your information, honestly, offence in itself is not deadly.
Offence in itself is not deadly if we do not harbour it.
If we do not what?
(Harbour it.)
If you do not what?
It is not deadly.
It becomes deadly if we hold or keep it in our hearts.
If you hold or keep offence in your heart, it becomes deadly.
When you keep offence in your heart, it produces so much fruit -
hurt, anger, bitterness, jealousy, outrage, resentment, hatred – just name it.
When you keep offence in your heart, it produces so much fruit such as hatred, anger,
unfaithfulness, rudeness, pride and so on and so forth.
Offence in itself is not deadly if we do not harbour or keep it.
In Luke 17, Jesus made it abundantly clear that it is impossible to live without being offended.
What does it mean?
It means we have to be ready, prepared and strongly armed for offence
because our response to it determines our future, determines your salvation.
When you are offended, it means you are not happy.
"Thank You, Jesus" is a response from a happy heart.
"Amen" is a response from a happy heart.
If someone says, "Amen!" and you are not happy - that is not for Jesus.
If you say, "Thank You, Jesus!" and you are not happy - it means it is not for Jesus.
If you say, "In Jesus' name!" and you are not happy - you are not talking to Jesus, you are talking to yourself.
When you are not happy, your spirit is imprisoned.
Jesus needs a free spirit.
It is a free spirit that can attract, have access to the Spirit of God.
When you are not happy, your spirit is imprisoned.
"Thank You, Jesus" is a response from a happy heart.
Not being happy can affect your health, your relationship with others and with God -
whether you are the accused or the accuser.
The problem is that if we get offended, we hardly realise that we are trapped.
"No - it is the one that abused me. It is the one that insulted me. I cannot understand that little boy
insulting me just like that."
When we get offended, we hardly realise that we are trapped, imprisoned.
We believe that we are on the right side.
Whether you are on the right or wrong side, not being happy is not good; it imprisons our spirit.
The interest of satan is for us to focus on the wrong done to us, "Ha, he slapped me".
We forget the reality, which is the consequence of that offence – attack, unhappiness, pain.
That is his interest.
He wants us to focus on the wrong done to us and forget the reality.
That is satan.
He wants to focus on the wrong done to you and forget the reality.
"Blessed are the pure in heart, for they shall see God."
It means blessed are those who are happy, who have a free spirit, for they shall see God.
If you are not happy, you cannot see God.
Whether you are wrong or right, accuser or accused, if you are not happy, you cannot see God.
Because you will focus on the wrong done to you and forget the reality.
Nowadays, we seem to experience so much division among believers, pastors, bishops,
the congregation, leaders in politics and business.
This is because there is a lack of real love.
The reason for this is that offence is so common, rampant.
Are you with me?
There is so much division among believers, leaders in politics and business,
professional gurus and the congregation.
The reason is offence is so rampant due to lack of real love.
Tell your neighbour: "Offence is so rampant due to lack of real love".
There is love but not real love.
The love we are talking about, the love of Christ, is not the love they play in politics.
Political parties A, B, and C will not allow the real love of Christ to be among themselves.
The reason for this is that offence is so common due to lack of real love.
Real love forgets wrong, so that there will be a future.
Tell your neighbour, "Real love forgets wrong, so that there will be a future."
The challenges you are facing today – no love, no future.
The world - no love, no future.
See what is happening all over the world - war, attacks.
No real love, no future.
In the face of real, genuine love, offence cannot stand.
Tell your neighbour, "In the face of real, genuine love, offence cannot stand."
What is offence in the face of real and genuine love?
For those of you who know the importance of the future, you dare hold offence.
We don't know the importance of future; you just want to live and enjoy today.
Each time you are enjoying yourself now, remember what will happen tomorrow.
Let me advise you:
it is impossible to establish a healthy relationship
with a person who has left one relationship bitter and offended.
When you divorce and marry another person, you will likely divorce again and marry another person -
unless you look into the root of that divorce - whether it had been settled or not.
It is impossible to establish a healthy, good, wonderful relationship
with a person who has left a relationship bitter and offended.
This is why you keep having broken homes, relationships with your business partners;
you don't have any genuine friends.
And you cannot achieve anything alone; you need good, inspired, informed people - but you can't get them.
If you leave a relationship bitter and offended,
you will enter the next relationship with that same attitude.
So, you can see reason why you keep having problems with your business partner.
Your business partner left previous relationship bitter and offended,
you too, you left previous relationship bitter and offended;
and you people come together to have a relationship that cannot work, unless both of you are healed.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Our offences can hold us in bondage.
This is it.
You can see why you are in bondage.
Because you left a relationship bitter and offended, you can never have any healthy relationship.
The Bible says, "Peace will enter relationship and we walk out of relationship with joy".
Situation should not break the relationship, no matter what happened,
but God that joined the relationship should be the One to separate you people.
It is impossible to establish a healthy relationship
with a person who has left a relationship bitter and offended.
Healthy relationship means good relationship.
If you are looking for a good relationship, make sure you meet someone
who did not leave a relationship bitter and offended.
That is why it is difficult for couples.
Out of ten marriages six hardly hold.
If you leave a relationship bitter and offended, go back and do the right thing.
You can leave a relationship with peace.
If you leave a relationship bitter and offended, you will enter the next relationship with the same attitude.
Sometimes, you will see me very quiet.
All what they've been saying about me for the past thirty years, "I'm this or that" - I will not talk.
This is the reason.
I have been very careful.
You can abuse me, tell all sorts of things about me; I will not talk - I will leave myself for prayer.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Someone who is a devil, pain to you today may be a saviour tomorrow.
You can be whatever you are to me today.
If you turn to be a devil today, I will look beyond you to see what you may become tomorrow.
Tomorrow is a mystery.
Relationships - be careful.
The person who is your enemy today can be your saviour tomorrow.
If you continue to use the actions of people today to judge them, you may have problems in the future.
"The man is very bad. The woman is very bad." - because they are very bad you take action;
you will likely have problems tomorrow.
You will receive in a moment what you have been seeking for years the moment you let offence go.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Whether you are right or wrong, holding a grudge against your neighbour -
you have already grieved the Holy Spirit -
because you are a spirit, living in a physical body, learning to live in the natural world.
Say to yourself, "I am a spirit, living in a physical body, learning to live in the natural world".
If you are a spirit, why are you now fighting your brother?
Our battle is not against flesh and blood.
Your brother is of blood and flesh.
You are a spirit and your battle is not against flesh and blood but against sprit-beings.
Pressure and tension.
Ask your neighbour, "Why are you fighting your brothers?"
They are flesh and blood and your battle is not against flesh and blood.
You are a spirit, living in a physical body, learning to live in the natural world.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You have to let the world know you are a spirit by acting this way,
by not fighting flesh and blood.
If your brother says, "I will deal with you", you say to yourself, "I'm a spirit; how can you deal with a spirit?"
The SCOAN Sunday Service
How can you deal with a spirit?
It is not possible.
You can't hold or touch the spirit.
Where will you see and fight the spirit?
You can only fight the flesh and blood.
Jesus made abundantly clear that it is impossible to live in this world without being offended.
Offence will come – don't harbour it.
Offence in itself is not deadly.
It will come; don't harbour it.
It is when you harbour offence and keep it in your heart it produces
anger, hatred, resentment, outrage and strife.
Once it produces hurt and anger, you are not happy any longer.
"Hallelujah" is a response from a happy heart.
Not being happy can affect your relationship with God, with others and your health.
Be happy.
For you to be happy, you must trust God's authority more than man's majority.
I want to believe you are free now.
(Amen!)
- Are you free?
- (Yes!)
The SCOAN Sunday Service
This response actually comes from a happy heart.
- Are you free?
- (Yes!)
(I am free!)
What do you mean by "you are free"?
I'm free in my heart.
By the spirit in my heart.
- By the spirit?
- Yes.
I want to believe you listen to the voice of your spirit because it is controlled by the Holy Spirit.
You have to feed your spirit; your spirit is hungry.
You are always feeding your flesh and you are a spirit.
Hunger wants to kill your spirit.
All this food you eat is not for your spirit, it is for your flesh.
You have to feed your spirit by allowing the Word of God.
Read the Word of God, meditate in it and keep it in your heart.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
The prophetic word God gave me is that He would touch your heart with this message.
I can see your heart has been touched.
(Amen.)
The SCOAN Sunday Service
There are many people you don't want to hear from.
Give them a phone call; just say, "Hi, I pray with you, I love you."
That word will go a long way.
The spiritual strength and grace of one grounded in the Word of God can identify good from evil,
separate good from evil and identify his traps for what they are.
You cannot just say, "I'm free".
Right now, start reconciliation and stop focusing on the wrong they have done to you.
Satan wants you to focus on the wrong people have done to you.
People should tell you...
There are many of us here that keep one, two or three persons in the prison.
You sentenced them to prison.
Find time to go to the prison and say you want to see such and such person.
By the time you enter you say, "You know me. Please, I want to pray with you."
Begin to think how you can release such person from the prison.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Are you with me?
When you leave here...
There are many persons that are in a prison because they have truly wronged you, they did evil to you.
Look for their custody and pay them a visit.
Enter the prison, wait for the person, counsel the person, pray with the person, and tell the person
that right from this moment you want this person to walk out, so they can release this person.
Drop the case.
Those things are not good for your future.
They Lord says, "I will set a table before you in the presence of the people you have imprisoned."
If you put them in the prison or kill, destroy them...
By the time God set a table they will not be there and He promised He would set a table for you
in the presence of these people that you had put in prison.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Tell your neighbour, "I will set a table before you in the presence of who?"
This enemy - you are killing, destroying, sending them to prison because of the position you have
and the right, the law of your nation, your country, many had been sentenced to death, to prison, killed...
So, by the time God set that table before you, in the presence of who?
... people you have killed.
People you have destroyed.
That is why this table is being delayed for many of us here.
By now, many of us would have enjoying this table,
but when the Lord realised that you had killed, destroyed a lot of your enemies
or you had sent them to prison - the table is unnecessary.
Think about that.
Change the kind of prayer you offer, "Die die die" - don't kill them, let them live
and see the table the Lord will set before you.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Take effort and begin to release those who you call an enemy wherever they are;
in the prison, wherever - meet them, counsel them, leave them.
Please, it is very important for your future.
For your future, forgiveness is very important.
For your future, release of your enemies is very important.
God bless you.
The SCOAN Sunday Service